(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)うん… うん…｡
うん そうだね そうするよ…｡
わかってるって…｡
うん… ありがとう…｡
[GinTama]
[This opening is a parody of "Ultraman."]
そうだね…｡
じゃあね｡
[VALENTINE'S DAY]
[SPECIAL EFFECT DELUSION SERIES]
[Note: Parody of SPECIAL EFFECT FANTASY SERIES of Ultraman.]
[SPACE OPERATION No.1]
[Note: Parody of Ultraman's first episode, "Ultra Operation No.1"]
[REMARKS]
でやっ！
[When watching TV,]
[make sure the room is well lit]
[and keep a good distance from the screen.]
[Enjoy the show. Coming up next...]
["GinTama" starts!]
[Monster Shogun Colonel Cherry appears.]
...Yeah...yeah...I know that.
Yeah, that's right. I'll do that. ...Yeah.
Thank you. That's right.
I'll talk to you later.
Duwa!
[Note: "Duwa" is a spoof of how Ultraman always says "Shuwa."]
[February 14th is national Valentine's day!! I heard it's the day bishop Valentine was executed...]
[...for fighting against the free marriage ban in 269 AD. It had nothing to do with chocolate, right?]
[Valentine's Day Fair]
(騒ぎ声)
This is Ketsuno reporting.
(結野ｱﾅ)こちら 現場の結野です｡
現在 街じゅうのﾁｮｺ売り場では
ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝ商戦で…｡
Currently, all chocolate shops have special Valentine's Day sales.
いたっ… ご覧のように
大変 混みあった状況で…｡
Ouch! As you can see, the shops are really crowded!
なにすんのよ！
What are you doing?!
Ugly girls like you can forget about Valentine's Day!
つうかなぁ お前らみたいなﾌﾞｽ➡
ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝもｸｿも 関係ないんじゃ！
Idiots!
ｵﾗｯ ﾊﾞｰｶ 死ね ﾌﾞｽが！
Die, you ugly girl!
Valentine's Day?
(神楽)ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝ？ 銀ちゃん➡
Gin-chan, what's Valentine's Day?
何ｱﾙか？ ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝって｡
(銀時)あぁ… そういや
今日 ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝか｡
Ah, today is Valentine's Day. I forgot about it.
忘れてたわ…
ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝつうのはだな➡
Valentine's Day is when a woman gives chocolates to a man to express her feelings for him.
女が男に ﾁｮｺとともに
好意を伝える日だ｡
そっか 今日 ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝか…
すっかり忘れてた｡
That's right, today is Valentine's Day. I completely forgot about it.
(新八)まぁ ﾎﾞｸら
関係ないですけどね｡
Well, it doesn't involve us.
これ映ってる人 ほとんど
義理ﾁｮｺでしょう？
Most people on TV are probably buying "obligation chocolate," right?
悪しき風習ですよね…
建前で そういうことするのって｡
It's a bad custom. They have such devious intentions.
だいたい ｳﾁの国は おかしいよ｡
Anyway, our country is really strange.
やれ ｸﾘｽﾏｽだ ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝだ…｡
We have Christmas and Valentine's Day... Yet we still celebrate traditional New Year's, too.
そのくせ 正月とかも
やるんだもの｡
People have no principles at all. They just want an excuse to party, I guess.
節操ねえにも ほどがあるよ｡
ただ騒ぎたいだけだろ｡
ﾎﾝﾄですよね｡
I agree. In Japan, we only need to celebrate New Year's and Obon.
[Note: Obon is a Buddhist festival to honor ancestral spirits.]
日本は 盆と正月だけ
やってりゃいいんですよ｡
なんで ２人とも変な感じｱﾙか？
Why do you two look so different today?
えっ なに言ってんの？
いつもと変わらねえだろ｡
Huh?
What do you mean? We're no different than usual.
えっ 何か
期待しているように見えた？
Huh? Do we look like we were expecting something? Like chocolates?
ﾁｮｺ欲しいみたいな？
ちょっと やめてよ～｡
Hey, don't get us wrong. You sound like you think we're shameless guys.
すげえ 恥ずかしいﾔﾂら
みたいじゃん ｵﾚら！
ﾊﾊﾊｯ ﾁｮｺなんて いつでも
食べられますもんね｡
We can eat chocolates any time.
ってか 自分で買うし みたいな？
We can always buy them ourselves.
あれっ でも新八…
お前 なんかちょっとｲﾒﾁｪﾝした？
Huh? But Shipachi, did you change your look a bit?
えっ 全然ですけど？
Huh? Not at all. Ah, I woke up this morning with "bed head," so that's probably it.
あっ 今日 寝癖 ひどかったから
それかな？
Gin-san, you look really chic today, too.
銀さんこそ 今日 なんか
ｼｯｸに見えますけど？
お前は ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝ
意識しすぎなんだよ｡
You're too conscious of Valentine's Day.
ｵﾚは いつもと変わらんよ｡
I'm no different today than usual.
I'm the same as always, the same Gin-san you know and love.
いつもと同じ
みんなの銀さんだよ｡
(玄関ﾁｬｲﾑ)
Yes!
(新八/銀時)はいぃ～っ！
Wait! Gin-san, I'll get the door. Let me do it!
ちょっと 銀さん
ﾎﾞｸが出ますって ﾎﾞｸが！
いやっ たまにはｵﾚが！
No, let me do it this time. What? Are you expecting someone to bring chocolates?
お前 ひょっとして
誰かがﾁｮｺを持ってきたとか➡
Ah. You, too.
期待してんの？
あっ お前もｱﾙか…｡
(ｶﾞｽ屋)すみません ｶﾞｽの集金です｡
Excuse me. I came to collect gas fees.
(銀時/新八)
お呼びじゃねえんだよ！
You're not invited!
(ｶﾞｽ屋の悲鳴)
ﾊｧ… 神様 どうか
あの哀れな男たちにﾁｮｺを…｡
God, please give some chocolate to those pathetic men.
Wh-What?!
なんだ？
Hey! What the heck is this?!
おい いったい何事だ？
空から…｡
From the sky...
(神楽)でっかいﾁｮｺが…｡
...a huge piece of chocolate...
《ｳｪﾙｶｰﾑ！》
《ﾒｶﾞﾄﾝﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝ!!》
Welcome!
Megaton Valentine's Day!
あぁ これ ｵﾚ宛てだわ…｡
Ah, this must be for me. It's probably from Setsuko-chan from the teahouse.
きっと たぶん
茶屋の節子ちゃんが…｡
いや ﾎﾞｸですよ たぶん！
No! Perhaps it's for me!
It may be from Sayaka-chan, who went to the temple school with me.
寺子屋のとき 一緒だった
さやかちゃんが…｡
Ah...hey... Please don't touch my belongings without permission.
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)あっ ちょっ…｡
人の物に 勝手に
触らないでくれないか？
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)それは私の物だ｡
That's mine.
こちらに返したまえ｡
Give it back to me.
["Even A Hero Has Issues"]
All right.
(警官)はい じゃあ ここに
ﾊｰｯと息 吐いて｡
Breathe into this!
ﾊｰｯ｡
Ah, it's higher than the acceptable limit. You've been drinking, haven't you?
あぁ 規定値 軽く超えてるね…
飲んでるね？ ﾁﾐ｡
おまわりさん…
免停は 勘弁してもらえないか？
Mr. Policeman, could you please not suspend my flying license?
空が飛べないと
私は 仕事ができない｡
If I can't fly in the sky, I won't be able to work.
怪獣が出たとき
どうすればいいんですか｡
What will I do when the monsters appear?
Well, but I'm just doing my job, too.
いや こっちも仕事だからね｡
幸い こちらの方たち
修理代を出すなら➡
Fortunately, these people say that, as long as you pay for repairs, they won't press charges.
法的な手続きはとらないって
言ってくれてるから｡
今度から気をつけてね｡
Please be more careful in the future.
飲んだら飛ぶな 飛ぶなら飲むな｡
Don't fly after drinking, and don't drink if you fly. It's common sense.
常識でしょ？
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)はい…｡
Yes...
(警官)じゃ あとで署に
顔 出してね｡
Well, come down to the station later.
I'm sorry! I caused you a lot of trouble.
すまない！
本当に迷惑をかけた…｡
いやいや… もういいですから｡
No, no, no, no, no! It's all right.
幸い ｹｶﾞ人も出なかったし｡
Luckily, no one was injured. You needn't bow to us.
頭を上げてください｡
Well... Um... Huh? Well, you're a kind of hero from outer space, aren't you?
[Note: Shinpachi is posing like Ultraman.]
つうか あの… えっ？
あの… 宇宙から来た…
ﾋｰﾛｰ的な人… ですよね？
いや ﾋｰﾛｰっていうかﾋﾛｲﾝだな
一応 女の子なんで…｡
Well, not a hero, but a heroine. I'm a girl.
あぁ そうなんだ！
Ah... I see.
ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝというのを
やらせてもらっている！
I'm doing it as the so-called Spacewoman.
[Note: Parody of Ultraman.]
あぁ じゃあ やっぱり
お仕事のほうは➡
Ah, then your job is to kind of protect the Earth, right?
地球を守る的な
あれなんですかね？
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)いや 地球には 出張で｡
出張!?
No, I came to Earth on a business trip.
Business trip? Your job has business trips?!
出張なんかあんの？
Sorry, but I am not assigned to a small-scale area, like Earth.
悪いが 地球限定などという
小さい規模で活動はしていない｡
見たとおりのｽｹｰﾙだ｡
You see I am in charge of a much larger area.
I work day and night to keep peace in the universe.
宇宙全体の平和を守るため
日夜 活動している｡
すごいですね！
ｽｹｰﾙでかいや!! やっぱり｡
It sounds amazing. Your work area is huge.
月火が家事手伝い｡
[Weekly schedule]
Monday and Tuesday, I help out around the house.
[Mon & Tue: Housekeeping]
水から金が実家周りをﾊﾟﾄﾛｰﾙで➡
And Wednesday through Friday, I patrol around the house.
[Weekly schedule]
[Mon & Tue: Housekeeping]
[Wed  Thus  Fri: Patrol around the house]
[Weekly schedule]
[Mon & Tue: Housekeeping]
[Wed  Thus  Fri: Patrol around the house]
[Sat & Sun: Off]
週休２日制だな｡
I have a five-day workweek.
Hey! You're just protecting your own home then!
おい！
実家しか守ってねえじゃねえか!!
By the way, um... that thing...
それで あのさっきの あれは？
あぁ あのﾁｮｺのことですか？
Ah, you mean the chocolate?
(神楽)残念ながら落ちたｼｮｯｸで
割れてしまったようｱﾙ！
Sorry to say this, but a piece broke off after it hit the ground.
No, there are teeth marks on it.
いや 歯形ついてんだけど…｡
I was trying to do my best, but...
私も何とかしようと
がんばったんだけど…｡
何をがんばったんだよ｡
Do your best for what?
I see. I made the mistake of drinking to help me get over my nervousness.
そうか… 緊張をお酒で
ちらそうとしたのが間違いだった｡
緊張って…
じゃあ やっぱり このﾁｮｺ➡
Nervousness... Were you planning on giving this chocolate to somebody?
誰かに
あげるつもりだったんですか？
おい なんか お悩みなら
話を聞こうか？
Hey, it looks like you're worried about something. Can we help?
ｵﾚはな
万事屋 銀ちゃんといって➡
You know, I'm Gin of the Odd Jobs. You're a hero who protects the universe.
お前が宇宙を守るﾋｰﾛｰなら
ｵﾚは いわば➡
I have similar duties. I'm like a hero who protects Edo. Sort of!
江戸を守る
ﾋｰﾛｰ的な存在といっていい！
ほとんど！
ほとんどｳｿだろうが!!
That's sort of a lie! And you're trying to look cool by eating the chocolate.
っつうか ｵﾒｴがかっこつけて
食ってる それが原因なんだよ！
The chocolate is the problem!
黙っとけ！ お前は｡
Shut up! She's the heroine who ensures peace in the universe.
宇宙の平和を守ってるﾋﾛｲﾝ様だぜ
相当 貯め込んでるぜ！
She must have a lot of money. This woman could be a real sucker.
このｱﾏ いいｶﾓだ！
困ってるﾋﾛｲﾝ様に なに…
ｱﾝﾀが悪の根源だよ!!
How can you say something like that about a helpless heroine?
You're the root of all evil.
(ｶﾗｰﾀｲﾏｰの音)
Ah!
Something that looks like a timer is blinking!
なんか
ﾀｲﾏｰ的なものが点滅してる！
Don't tell me! You have to leave Earth!
[Note: Ultraman has a timer on his chest that gives him three minutes before he has to leave Earth.]
まさか もう地球から出ないと！
いや そういうんじゃなくて…｡
No, it's nothing like that.
But every three minutes, I have to call home. Otherwise...
３分に１回
実家に電話しないとﾀﾞﾒなんだ｡
じゃないと… 都会の荒波に
飲み込まれそうになる｡
...I feel like I've been sucked into the wild urban jungle of the big city.
都会に負けそうになる｡
どんだけ実家に帰りたいの！
I'd feel like I'm losing my roots.
How badly do you want to go home?!
Ah, Mom? Yeah, I'm fine. Ah, thanks for the rice. I'm eating well.
あっ ｵｶﾝ？
うん 元気にやってるよ｡
あぁ お米ありがとう！
食べてるよ!!
３分に１回って
お母さんのほうも➡
Every three minutes? What kind of life does her mom have?
いったい
どんな生活してるんですかね？
常にｽﾀﾝﾊﾞｲですか！
She's always standing by?
うん そうだね…
いや そんな いないよ！
Yes, that's right.
No... I don't have someone like that. I'm too busy working, so... Yeah... Well... Wait...
やっぱ仕事が忙しいからさ｡
うん いや ちょっと…｡
Enough already! I'm ensuring peace in the universe!
いいかげんにしてよ！
こっちは宇宙の平和を守ってんの｡
孫の顔が見たいとか
そんな次元で生きてないの！
You want a grandchild, but I don't live that kind of vulgar life!
なんか 超気まずい感じで
切っちゃったんですけど…｡
It looks like she hung up in a huff.
なんで こんな超人的なﾔﾂらの
親子ｹﾞﾝｶ 見なきゃいけねえんだよ｡
Why do we have to hear about this superwoman's family quarrels?
(轟音)
Huh?
なんだ？ あれ｡
What's that?
(騒ぎ声)
(衝撃音)
(ﾁｪﾘｰ大佐)ぐおぉ～！
(女)ｷｬ～ か… 怪獣よ！
I-It's a monster!
ｶﾞｧ～ｯ！
あぁ… ｷｬ～！
(足音)
(悲鳴)
ﾊｧﾊｧ… ﾊｧﾊｧ…｡
ｳｰﾏﾝさん！ あの怪獣は？
Woman-san! That monster is...!
ｽﾍﾟちゃん！ あれを倒すため
地球へ来たｱﾙか？
Supe-chan! Did you come to Earth to defeat him?
あっ…｡
Huh?
ん？ どうかしたか？
What's wrong?
私は 今年で37歳になる｡
I'm going to be 37 years old this year.
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)
結婚適齢期を とっくに過ぎた➡
I passed the marriageable age a long time ago and am a so-called loser.
世間でいう いわゆる負け組だ｡
((怪獣:ｷﾞｬ～！
(怪獣)ｷﾞｬ～!!))
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)脇目も振らず
宇宙の平和を守っていたら➡
I was so focused on ensuring peace in the universe, that before I knew it,
いつのまにか
こんな ｵﾊﾞさんになっていた｡
I had become an old woman.
どんな いい女でも
隙がなければ➡
No matter how good a woman is,
if she doesn't give a man a chance, no one will pursue her.
男は口説いてこないというが
私が まさに そうだった｡
That's my problem.
宇宙の平和を守る私には
一分の隙もなかった｡
As I was protecting the peace of the universe, I never gave anyone a chance.
だって
宇宙の平和を守っているからな｡
Because I was too busy protecting the peace in the universe!
隙なんて見せたら
怪獣に後ろからｶﾞﾌﾞﾘだ！
If I give anyone a chance and get distracted, the monsters will win.
そんな
ろくに恋愛経験のない私だ｡
I've hardly ever been in love.
悪い男にも ひっかかる｡
I've been deceived by bad guys...
妻子をもった上司との危険な恋｡
I was even in a dangerous love affair with my boss, who had a wife and children.
そのうち別れるという
言葉を信じて➡
I believed him when he said he would get a divorce someday, and I cried so many times.
何度 泣いたことか…｡
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)ある日 私は
ｶﾞﾏﾝできなくなって➡
One day, I had endured too much. I followed him in an attempt to destroy his family.
彼の家庭をﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬにしてやろうと
彼をつけた｡
Duwa!
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)でも見てしまった！
But then I saw him!
家族と一緒にいるときの彼…｡
When he was with his family,
私といるときには
決して見せることのない➡
he had a warm smile that I'd never seen before. Then I thought...
笑顔を見たとき 私は思った｡
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)私のﾊﾞﾅｼﾞｳﾑ光線は➡
My Vanadium Ray can't be used to destroy other people's happiness.
[Note: Vanadium Ray is a parody of Specium Ray from Ultraman.]
幸せを破壊するために
あるんじゃないと…｡
お前 どこがﾋﾛｲﾝ？
ただのすえたOLだろうが！
What kind of heroine are you? You're just a plain office lady!
I was really lonely. I just wanted someone to talk to.
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)寂しかったんだ！
私は ただ人恋しくて…｡
だから あんなﾔﾂと…｡
That's why I was with that kind of guy.
Since then, I've hit bottom.
それからの私は 荒れに荒れた｡
夜な夜な盛り場を徘徊し
毎晩いろんな怪獣と夜をともに…｡
I hung around nightspots night after night, and I spent time with all kinds of monsters.
なんで怪獣!?
Why monsters?!
I learned a lot of skills, like using the Vanadium Ray.
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)ﾊﾞﾅｼﾞｳﾑ光線以外にも
いろいろな技を覚えた｡
どんな技だよ!?
What kind of skills?!
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)そんなとき
疲れ 渇き 絶望し➡
And... When I was tired, drained, full of despair
倒れた私の前に現れたのが
彼だった｡
and had really fallen, he appeared.
(店主)お客さん
もう店 閉めますよ｡
Sir, I'm closing the bar.
起きてください お客さん
家族の方 心配しますよ！
Please wake up, sir. Your family will be worried.
＜ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ:彼は…
私と まったく同じ｡
He was just like me. No, he was the total opposite.
いや… まったく
逆ともいえる存在だった…＞
(ﾁｪﾘｰ)いいんだよ…｡
That's all right. There's no one at home, anyway.
(ﾁｪﾘｰ)どうせ 家 帰ったって
誰も いねえもん…｡ ﾋｯｸ！
＜ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ:そう！
宇宙を 征服するために➡
Right... In order to conquer the universe,
わき目もふらず 走り続け➡
he devoted himself to conquering space and passed the marriageable age.
婚期を 逃した男…｡
I felt he would understand me.
彼なら
私を 理解してくれる気がする｡
I felt he would accept me.
彼なら…
私を 受け入れてくれる気がする｡
そう… 彼なら！
Right... He...
怪獣将軍 ﾁｪﾘｰ大佐＞
Monster Shogun Colonel Cherry!
(新八たち)えぇ～っ…!?
(銀時たち)えっ…!?
Huh?
えっ？ ｱｲﾂ!?
That guy?
えぇ～っ!?
ｱﾝﾀ 敵の怪獣の大将に➡
What?!
Are you going to give Valentine's Day chocolates to Monster Shogun, the enemy?!
ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝﾁｮｺ
あげるつもりだったの!?
いやいや いやいや！
おかしい！ おかしいって!!
No, no, no, no! That's ridiculous! Ridiculous!
婚期が 遅れてるからって
おかしくなってる あなたは!!
Even if you've passed the marriageable age, you're being ridiculous!
In order to lure their general out, I've defeated numerous monsters.
大将の あの人を
舞台に 引きずり出すため➡
私は 今まで
数々の怪獣を 倒してきた｡
ｱﾝﾀ 宇宙平和のために
戦ってんじゃないのかよ!!
I thought you were fighting for the sake of protecting peace in the universe!
ようやく来た このとき｡
Finally the time has come. Now is my only chance to declare my love.
告白するのは… 今しかない！
おい… 婚期のことしか
考えてねえよ この人！
Hey! This woman is only thinking about marriageable age issues!
Calm down, Shinpachi. The opponent is the enemy's general.
落ち着け 新八｡
相手は 敵の大将だ｡
If her love declaration succeeds, then they'll reconcile and the universe will be at peace.
告白が成功すれば 和睦が成立し
宇宙は 平和になるぞ｡
That kind of universal peace is just disgusting!
なに その 気持悪い宇宙平和！
You, Spacewoman, have finally come!
(ﾁｪﾘｰ)
おのれ ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ！ 来おったか！
ﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝで はしゃぐ ｶｯﾌﾟﾙのｼﾞｬﾏをし
別れさせ！
Causing couples who are excited about Valentine's Day to break up...
子供の出生率を 下げ！
Causing the birthrate decline...
Causing the population decline...
人口を減らし！ なんやかんやで➡
And on and on... And my plans for taking over the universe...
宇宙を征服する ﾜｼの計画を…➡
ｼﾞｬﾏしに来おったか～!!
You dare disturb me?
あれ？ これ ほっといても
宇宙は 平和なんじゃないすか？
Huh? Even without things like that, the universe can still be peaceful, right?
Colonel Cherry. You're wrong. Today... Um... Well...
ﾁｪﾘｰ大佐… それは違う！
今日は… あの… その…｡
うわっ…！
どうしました!? 一応 敵ですよ！
What's the matter?! He's the enemy!
Why are you suddenly turning your back on him?!
いきなり 背なんか向けて！
To tell you the truth... I've never made any love declarations before.
実は… 私は 今まで➡
告白というものを
したことがない…｡
Don't worry. Supe-chan, you're the heroine of the universe.
大丈夫ね！
ｽﾍﾟちゃんは 宇宙のﾋﾛｲﾝ！
You must've overcome all your hardships.
今まで どんなﾋﾟﾝﾁも
乗り越えてきたはずね！
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)そう…｡
私は いつだって➡
Yes, I always rushed to people when they requested help.
人々が 助けを求めれば
こうして 駆けつけてきた｡
I always gave my body and heart to men whenever they wanted.
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)
いつだって 求められれば➡
身も心も 委ねてきた…｡
I was a convenient woman.
そんな 都合のいい女…｡
That's me.
それが 私だ！
おい～！
Hey! You're talking about a totally different subject!
なんか もう 意味 変わってんぞ！
そんな私に… 今さら…➡
A person like me... Now...
今さら… 青春まっさかり…➡
It's too late...
女子高生のような
青臭いことをできる勇気なんて…｡
For me to bring out courage like that of a high school girl...
ない…｡
...no way.
(笑い声)
I don't know what you're doing, but it's foolish to turn your back on your enemy.
(ﾁｪﾘｰ)なんか わからんが
敵に背を向けるとは 愚かな！
Whoa! This is bad! Woman-san!
まずい！ ｳｰﾏﾝさん!!
Take this!
くらえ～!!
うおっ…！
(上司)待て～!!
Wait!
Duwa!
ﾃﾞｭﾜ…！
Deden...
(上司)でで～ん！
Hmm... A rookie?
(ﾁｪﾘｰ)むぅ… 新手か！
He's on our side, right?! He must be here to save us!
味方ですよね!? あの人！
きっと
助けにきてくれたんですよ！
(新八たち)うわ～っ…！
Ouch!
ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ…｡
Spacewoman...
ﾋﾛｼさん…｡
えっ…？
Hiroshi-san...
Eh...
I've separated with my wife!
Come back to me!
妻とは 別れた！
ﾎﾞｸのもとに 帰ってきてくれ!!
I love only you!
愛しているのは ｷﾐだけだ！
What?!
えぇ～っ!? ｱﾝﾀ 例の上司!?
You're the boss she was talking about?!
つうか
怪獣 倒しにきたんじゃないの!?
We thought you came here to defeat the monster!
It's too late now! I can't believe what you just said!
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)今さら 遅すぎよ！
そんな言葉 信じられない！
Please! Let's start over again! And let's open a ranch in Argentina!
[Note: Spoof of the musical movie "Down Argentine Way."]
お願いだ… ２人で やり直そう！
そして ｱﾙｾﾞﾝﾁﾝで 牧場を開こう！
やめて!!
Stop it!
Duwa...
ﾃﾞｭﾜ…｡
ﾃﾞｭﾜ…！
Duwa...
...You really hate me...
(上司)そんなに 嫌がるのか…｡
But, I can't back out now...
でも…
ﾎﾞｸは もう あとには引けない｡
力ずくでも… ﾃﾞｭﾜ！
I'll make you come with me, even by force... Duwa!
なんすか？ この雰囲気…｡
What kind of atmosphere is this? It looks like another opponent has arrived.
つうか
戦う相手 増えてませんか？
I don't get it. What kind of lovers' spat is this?
意味 わかんねえ｡ どういうｽｹｰﾙの
痴話ｹﾞﾝｶなんだよ！
《嫌がってなんてない…｡
I don't hate him... Rather... My heart is trembling...
むしろ…
この期に及んで 心が揺れてる…｡
なんて 弱いの!? 私の気持！》
Why is it so weak...my heart?!
Supe-chan, don't believe him!
ｽﾍﾟちゃん 信じちゃﾀﾞﾒよ！
He can't commit to his own family!
That means he can't commit to you, either!
自分の家庭を 守れなかった男ね！
ｽﾍﾟちゃんのことも 守れないね!!
(ｶﾗｰﾀｲﾏｰの音)
Hello, Mom!
もしもし？ ｵｶﾝ！
さっきは ごめん…｡ うん…｡
Sorry about earlier... Yes... I'm busy now, but I wanted to call you...
今 取り込んでる…｡
だけど
どうしても 電話したくて…｡
Listen, Mom has something to tell you. Your daddy's health...
[TEL](ｽﾍﾟｰｽｵｶﾝ)あんな お母ちゃん➡
ｱﾝﾀに 言うてないことが
あったんや…｡
[TEL]お父ちゃんの体…➡
...He won't last two years.
あと２年… もたんねん…｡
So...at the very least. I hope he can see his grandchild.
[TEL](ｽﾍﾟｰｽｵｶﾝ)せやからな
せめて お父ちゃんに➡
孫の顔だけでも
見せてやってほしいんや！
Mom...
ｵｶﾝ…｡
[TEL](ｽﾍﾟｰｽｵﾄﾝ)ｱｷｺ！
ｵﾄﾝ…！
Akiko...
Dad!
[TEL]お母ちゃん…
あない 言うとるけどな➡
Even if your mom says something like that...don't worry about it.
そない 気にすることないで…｡
(咳込む声)
But...my last wish is to see...my daughter's...
[TEL]でもな… 最後に 願うんは…
娘の…➡
...happiness as a woman...
お前の女としての 幸せや…｡
ｵﾄﾝ…｡
Dad...
[TEL](ｽﾍﾟｰｽｵﾄﾝ)幸せに なりいや…
ｱｷｺ…｡
I hope you'll be able to be happy...Akiko.
(電話が 切れる音)
《ｵﾄﾝのことを考えたら やっぱり
経済力のあるﾋﾛｼさんと…｡
Thinking about my dad,
I'd better go with Hiroshi-san, who has some economic clout...
でも 今の 私の心は…｡
But...my heart now...
…私 どうしたら？
I don't know what I should do...
私は ずっと
宇宙の平和のため 戦ってきた｡
I've been fighting to protect peace in the universe.
それは 人々の幸せのためだ｡
That was for the sake of people's happiness... But...
Duwa!
しかし 私は
自分の幸せのための 戦い方など➡
...I don't know how to fight for my own happiness.
知らないのだ》
What are you saying?!
何言ってんの…
ﾋｰﾛｰだって ﾋﾛｲﾝだって➡
Regardless of whether they're a hero or heroine,
自分が 幸せになる方法なんて
知らねえだろうよ｡
they don't know how to find happiness.
悟空が結婚して
子供つくるなんて…➡
Even with Goku getting married and having kids...
[Note: Goku is the main character of Dragon Ball.]
最初は 本人どころか
作者も知らなかったはずだ｡
Perhaps even the author, as well as Goku himself, didn't expect that.
ｵﾒｴも 今まで さんざん
人のために戦ってきたんだろ？
You've been fighting for other people for a long time, right?
Then it's okay if you are just a bit selfish.
There's nothing wrong with that, I guess.
だったら
少しくらい 自分のために➡
わがままになったって
ﾊﾞﾁは 当たんねえんじゃねえの？
ﾋﾛｼさん…｡
Hiroshi-san.
あなたの告白 とても嬉しかった｡
ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ…｡
I'm really happy to hear your declaration of love.
Spacewoman...
でも！
ﾃﾞｭｯ!?
However...!
Duwa?!
You're in the past! You're an enemy to my future happiness!
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)
あなたは 過去の男なの！
私の 幸せの未来への敵なの!!
What are you talking about, Spacewo-?
何を言い出すんだ ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰ…！
Derya!
ﾃﾞﾘｬｱ～!!
Good-bye, Hiroshi-san! Good-bye to the old me!
さようなら ﾋﾛｼさん！
さようなら 昔の私～っ!!
ﾊｯ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
Now, I can start being the new me.
これで 私は
新しい私へと旅立てる｡
ｱﾝﾀの上司が 先に旅立ってるよ！
That was way too harsh on your Boss!
どこが 少しのわがままなんだよ！
宇宙ｽｹｰﾙじゃねえかっ！
That's you being just "a bit selfish"?! That was way overboard!
ﾃﾞｭﾜｯ!!
(２人)ﾅﾏ言って
すみませんでした!!
Duwa!
I'm sorry for saying such a bold thing!
ﾀﾞｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ!!
仲間割れか ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ！
Fight among yourselves, Spacewoman!
２対１で来られたら
本当 どうしようかと思ったけど｡
I wouldn't know what to do if you two conspired against me!
助かったわ！
本当に助かったわ！
But I'm saved!
I'm really saved!
何をどうどうと言ってるｱﾙか!!
Why are you saying that with such confidence?!
ﾁｪｯ ﾁｪﾘｰ大佐… じ… じ 実は…｡
Co-Colonel Cherry... A-Actually...
ﾌﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ!!
What? You look like you've frozen up!
どうした？ 恐怖で
体が ｺﾁｺﾁではないか｡
ﾜｼが 手とり足とり
体を動かしてやろうか？
Am I too frightening an opponent for you?
(笑い声)
…て あれ？ 何これ？
Huh? What's this?!
おい な なんなんだよ おい！
何か 言い返してこいよ！
Hey, what's going on?! Come on!
Why won't you talk to me?!
な… な…｡
くっ かかってこんなら
ﾜｼからいくぞ～っ!!
If you don't fight me...
...I'll start attacking!
Take this!
てやあ～っ!!
あっ…！
Please...be gentle.
お願い 痛くしないで｡
お おい… 何これ？
なんだよ おい 何？
H-Hey, w-wait! W-What is this?!
What's wrong with you?!
さっきから 気持悪い!!
You've been acting so disgusting!
何やってんのよ
ｱﾝﾀ 正義の味方でしょ！
What are you doing?! You're on our side, right?!
そんなやつ さっさと
やっつけちゃいなさいよ!!
A guy like that...hurry up and beat him!
あれぇ？ あの子 さっきから
顔 赤くない？
Huh? That girl has been blushing for a while.
ちょっとなに？ ひょっとして
ｱｲﾂのこと 好きなんじゃないの？
What?! Could it be that she likes him?
Hey, shut up, girls!
おい 黙れよ 女子!!
そんなわけ ねえじゃん！
ふざけんな 黙れよ！
There's no way!
Stop joking! Shut up!
Tsk.
ﾁｪｯ！
おい ﾁｪﾘｰ！
Hey, Cherry! Cherry!
ﾁｪﾘｰって！
あぁ？
ちょっと 校舎裏まで来なよ｡
ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝさんが 話あるって｡
Come with us to the back of the school.
Spacewoman-san has something to say to you.
Wh-What?! I'm not going.
なんだよ ｵﾚ 行かねえよ！
部活あるし
ﾀﾞﾁ 向こうで 待たせてっからさ｡
I have to go to club activities and my friends are waiting for me.
Hey, Cherry, how many chocolates did you get today?
ﾁｪﾘｰさ 今日 ﾁｮｺ 何個もらった？
関係ねえだろ！ なんだよ！
もらってねえよ そんなもん！
It's none of your business! What?! I didn't get anything like that!
ほら！
あぁ～！
よかったね！
Well!
Ah! Hey!
That's great! Maybe you'll get one today!
今日 １個 もらえるかもよ～！
Wait...
や～め～ろ～よ～！
Stop it!
ﾁｪﾘｰ君！
Cherry-kun.
Oh, it's you, Pachie.
なんだよ ﾊﾟﾁ恵か！
Hey, Cherry-kun, this year your Valentine's Day will be...
ねぇ ﾁｪﾘｰ君の 今年のﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝ
もしかしたら➡
最高のﾊﾞﾚﾝﾀｲﾝに
なっちゃうかもよ！
...the best Valentine's Day ever!
うっせえよ ﾌﾞｽ｡
Shut up, ugly girl.
Gee.
くそ… どこ行った？ ｱｲﾂら…｡
Damn it. Where did they go?
おぉっ!? …ｽ ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ！
S-Spacewoman...
(２人)あの… あ…｡
Well... Ah...
なんだよ… お前 先言えよ｡
...What? You go first.
いや… ﾁｪﾘｰ君から｡
No... Cherry-kun, you go first...
(女子たち)
がんば～れ！ がんば～れ！
Come on! Go for it!
Spacewoman-san, tell him!
ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝさん 言っちゃいなよ！
私のﾁｮｺ 使って～！
Please use my chocolate!
Mine, too!
私のﾁｮｺも！
私のも！
And mine!
私も！
これも！
Mine, too!
Me, too!
This, too!
私も！
(みんな)がんばれ！ ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ！
Me, too!
Good luck, Spacewoman!
Wh-What are you girls doing?!
なっ 何やってんだよ お前ら！
ﾁｪﾘｰ君！
えっ おっ？
Cherry-kun...
私の気持 受け取ってくれる？
Will you accept my heart?
ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ…｡
...Spacewoman...
ﾁｪﾘｰ君…｡
Cherry-kun...
♪♪～
なんか… 重い…｡
こんなことされても｡
It's like...
...embarrassing.
You doing something like this to me...
ﾃﾞｭﾜｱｱ～!!
Deyaa!
(ﾁｪﾘｰ)ああ～！ だっはぁ～!!
ああっ!!
(ｶﾗｰﾀｲﾏｰの音)
(ｽﾍﾟｰｽｳｰﾏﾝ)あぁ ｵｶﾝ？ うん｡
Ah, Mom? Yes. Today, I...protected the peace...of the universe.
今日も 私…
宇宙の平和… 守った｡
[Preview]
Kill me! Kill me!
Even if I live, I'm just destined to dance a bloody rondo all my life.
[Note: Rondo is music used for a circular dance.]
Please finish me now!
The next episode... "When Riding A Train, Make Sure You Grab The Straps With Both Hands."
[He was arrested on charges of being a pervert. Madao, Taizo Hasegawa (38 years old).]
[He tries to clear himself of a false accusation, but Prosecutor Haga challenges him!]